<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An excellent new song of the unfortunate Whig's To the tune of, The King enjoys his own again.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B22742</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99827982</idno>
  <idno type="VID">207649</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248496265</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E3831</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99827982</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99827982e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B22742)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 207649)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1925:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An excellent new song of the unfortunate Whig's To the tune of, The King enjoys his own again.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for S. Maurel,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>in the year, 168[2?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Verse - "The Whigs are but small, and of no good race,".</note>
                  <note>Publication date in Wing: 1682.</note>
                  <note>Copy imprint date has been smudged or crossed out; "1682" written in MS. below.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Ballads, English --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>John Pas </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="song">
            <pb facs="tcp:207649:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:207649:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>An Excellent New Song</hi> OF The Unfortunate WHIG's.</head>
            <opener>
               <hi>To the Tune of,</hi> The King enjoys his own again.</opener>
            <lg n="1">
               <head>[1]</head>
               <l>THe <hi>Whigs</hi> are but small, and of no good Race,</l>
               <l>and are Belov'd by very few;</l>
               <l>Old <hi>Tony</hi> broach'd his Tap in e'ry place,</l>
               <l>to encourage all his Factious Crew:</l>
               <l>At some great Houses in this Town,</l>
               <l>The <hi>Whiggs</hi> of High Renown,</l>
               <l>And all with a true Blue was their Stain;</l>
               <l>For since it is so,</l>
               <l>They have wrought their overthrow</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Old</hi> Tony <hi>will ne'r enjoy his own again.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="2">
               <head>[2]</head>
               <l>They all owne Duty to their Lawful Prince,</l>
               <l>and Loyal Subjects should have been,</l>
               <l>But their Duty is worn out long since,</l>
               <l>by the <hi>Association</hi> seen:</l>
               <l>But these are the <hi>Whiggs,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That have cut off some Legs,</l>
               <l>And fain would be at that Sport amain;</l>
               <l>For since it is so,</l>
               <l>They have wrought their overthrow,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Old</hi> Tony <hi>will ne'r enjoy his own again.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="3">
               <head>[3]</head>
               <l>And yet they are the Sham-pretenders,</l>
               <l>and they swear they'll support our Laws,</l>
               <l>These be the great Defenders of</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Ignoramus</hi> and the <hi>Old Cause:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>They'll defend the King,</l>
               <l>By Swearing of the Thing,</l>
               <l>These are the cursed Rogues in grain;</l>
               <l>For since it is so,</l>
               <l>They have wrought their overthrow,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Old</hi> Tony <hi>will ne'r enjoy his own again.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="4">
               <head>[4]</head>
               <l>The True Religion that shall down,</l>
               <l>which so along has won the day,</l>
               <l>And <hi>Common-Prayer</hi> i'th Church of e'ry Town,</l>
               <l>if that the <hi>Whiggs</hi> could but bear the Sway:</l>
               <l>For <hi>Oats</hi> he does begin,</l>
               <l>Now for to bring them in,</l>
               <l>As when he came mumping from <hi>Spain;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For since it so,</l>
               <l>They have wrought their overthrow,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Old</hi> Tony <hi>will ne'r enjoy his own again.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="5">
               <head>[5]</head>
               <l>How all their Shamming Plots they would hide,</l>
               <l>yet they are Ignorant they say,</l>
               <l>When as Old <hi>Tony</hi> he was Try'd,</l>
               <l>and brought off with <hi>Ignoramus</hi> sway:</l>
               <l>Then <hi>Oats</hi> he was Dumb,</l>
               <l>And could not use his Tongue,</l>
               <l>This is the Shamming Ro—in Grain;</l>
               <l>For since it is so,</l>
               <l>They have wrought their overthrow.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Old</hi> Tony <hi>will ne'r enjoy his own again.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="6">
               <head>[6]</head>
               <l>Then let all true Subjects Sing.</l>
               <l>and Damn the power of all those,</l>
               <l>That won't shew Loyalty to their King,</l>
               <l>and assist him against his Whiggish Foes:</l>
               <l>Then in this our happy state,</l>
               <l>In spight of Traytors hate,</l>
               <l>We will all Loyal still remain;</l>
               <l>For since it is so,</l>
               <l>They have wrought their overthrow,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Old</hi> Tony <hi>will ne'r enjoy his own again.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg n="7">
               <head>[7]</head>
               <l>God preserve our Gracious King,</l>
               <l>with the Royal Consort of his Bed,</l>
               <l>And let all Loyal Subjects sing,</l>
               <l>that the Crown may remain on <hi>Charles</hi>'s head:</l>
               <l>For we will drink his Health,</l>
               <l>In spight of <hi>Common-Wealth,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And his Lawful Rights we will maintain,</l>
               <l>For since it is so,</l>
               <l>They have wrought their overthrow,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Old</hi> Tony <hi>will ne'r enjoy his own again.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed for <hi>S. Maurel,</hi> in the Year, 168<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>▪</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>